# **Milton Lerner**

### **Personal details**

Phone: 050-2267912

Email: oso.lindo@gmail.com

City: Ramat Gan

## Languages

• **Hebrew**: Native.

- English: Proficient speaking, reading & writing.
- Spanish: Proficient speaking, reading & writing.

## **Skills**

### **Programming:**

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Angular, Node.JS, GraphQL, HTML5, CSS, MongoDB, FireBase, MySQL, PHP.

### Office:

Excel, PowerPoint, Word.

## **Course Projects**

- Supermarket website
   programmed with Angular, TypeScript,
   Node.Js, Express, MySQL & Bootstrap.
- Vacation website
   programmed with React, Redux, Node.JS
   MySQL, Socket.io, TypeScript, Express
   & Bootstrap.

## Links

Linkedin

## **Summary**

I'm a former financial analyst with 4 years of experience, passionate about code developing & creating highly polished user experience. I have high learning abilities, high personal standards, attention to details, & hunger for expanding my horizons. A team player with good interpersonal skills with both peers & superiors.

## **Experience**

04/2021 - Today: Freelance at Coda Project & Stance

- LatetPe App: Developing a play app that helps parents & children to create better communication in order to increase the child's protection.
  - Developed UI components that are highly UX driven.
  - Managed application's state in the client side.
  - Developed server side using Express with code optimizations for high response.
  - Created schemas using GraphQL & handled HTTP requests end-to-end.
  - Integrated with Firebase.

**Technologies**: ReactJS, Node.JS, GraphQL, TypeScript, Firebase.

- **Stance App**: Developing the server side of a news app.
  - Used Mongoose schema models for communication between the client & the server.
  - Defined & developed HTTP APIs in the server side using Express that implements CRUD methods for the Mongoose schema models.

Techonlogies: Node.js, MongoDB.

#### 2016 - 2021: MNS Consulting

- Composed complex financial models to support decision-making process for public-private partnership projects (PPP/PFI/BOT);
- Prepared expert economic opinions, equity valuations, & other financial valuations.
- Produced financial modelling to estimate overhead & costs of logistics project for Ministry of Defence (~\$4B); recommendations were accepted by client & implemented.

### **Education**

2020-2021: John Bryce - Full Stack Web Developer - GPA 94

• Learned & practiced the following web programming languages & technologies: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Angular, Node.JS, GraphQL, HTML5, CSS, MongoDB, Bootstrap, MaterialUI, MySQL, PHP, jQuery, Express.

2014 – 2016: Ben Gurion University, M.A. in Economics – GPA 94.5.

2011 – 2013: **Ben Gurion University, B.A. in Economics** – GPA 92 (Graduated with honors).